# Siyi Wei

Fresh Graduate With Bachelor Degree



♥ Toronto, Canada 647-870-8349

siyia.wei@mail.utoronto.ca

www.wei-siyi.com

aithub.com/superp0tat0

## Skills:

## **Programming:**

Advanced:

Python/R/MATLAB/C#/SQL TensorFlow/Linux (Ubuntu)/Git Keras/Pytorch/Scikit-Learn **Experienced:** Java/C/Jenkins/Docker/CUDA

Apache Hadoop

#### Data Science:

Advanced:

Feature Engineering Data Modelling/Visualization Machine Learning algorithms Statistical Analysis

## About me:

I am an active student who focus on statistical learning related questions and applications. I am also passionate on discovering the cutting-edge challenges in interdisciplinary area between statistics and computer science. Driven by my passion, I keep building relative research and teaching experiences. Beyond university work, he has attended DataFest UofT 2019, AmpHack RBC 2019 and **Business Data Science** Challenge Statistics Canada 2020 as data scientist.

#### Education

Candidate Honours Bachelor of Science at University of Toronto Scarborough May 2015 - Present

- Specialist in Statistics: Statistical Machine Learning and Data Mining
- Minor in Computer Science
- Relevant Courses:
  - CSCC11 Intro to Machine Learning (85) / CSC413 Deep Learning (Audit)
  - STAD68 Advanced Statistical Learning (88)
  - STAD57 Time Series (85) / STAD80 Big Data (On going)

#### **Work Experience**

QA Analyst and Web development, Rakuten Kobo

January – May 2019 Relevant Skills: C#/Ruby/QA/Git/Docker/Jenkins/SQL

- Composed QA web story using Jenkins, Ruby and selenium. Helping team analyze customer behaviors through Google analytics. Wrote SQL scripts for test automation and data extraction.
- Delivered stories following custom Agile management and report to release manager during daily release meetings.
- Develop New kobo subscription plan web page and API services using C#, report it to product manager.

Teaching Assistant, University of Toronto Scarborough

August 2018 – Now Relevant Skills: MATLAB/Python/NumPy/SkLearn

- CSCC11: Introduction to Machine Learning and Data Mining
- CSCA08: Introduction to Programming
- MATA22/24: Linear Algebra I&II STAB23: Statistics for Social Science

### **Project Experience**

Personal Website and Blogs (Personal Project)

September 2019 – Present. Relevant Skills: Programming/Writing Skills

Speech Recognition for mental health data (Research Project)

January 2020 – Present

Relevant Skills: Ubuntu/Shell Commands

Contribute to open source code by fixing the bugs of COVFEFE on GitHub. Successfully transfer audio to text for mental health related conversations.

Nominal GDP prediction (Competition for Business Data Science Challenge 2020) January 2020 – Present Relevant Skills: Python/LSTM/Time Series

Predict Nominal GDP for different industry sectors using LSTM and ARIMA.

Anti-plagiarism Statistical Analysis (Research Project)

January 2020 – Present

Relevant Skills: R/Cluster Analysis/PCA

Analyze the pattern of collected MOSS (anti-plagiarism program) data using R. Visualize the data pattern through R shiny.

Automation for ARIMA (Academic Project for times-series analysis in R) August – December 2019 Relevant Skills: R/Time Series

Automate the program for external resources selection in GDP deflators prediction. The improved model decreases the MAPE from 11.77% to 9.37%.